now we know how blender functions let's
现在我们了解了搅拌机的功能 让我们
start building that donut so as before
像以前一样开始建造甜甜圈
Let's uh well first of all just to
让我们 嗯 首先 只是为了
repeat make sure you are working with a
重复一遍 确保您使用的是
new scene completely new scene don't
新场景完全新场景不
want any remaining monkey heads lying
希望剩下的猴头躺在床上
around let's begin fresh slate and let's
让我们重新开始 让我们
delete our default Cube just with the
删除我们的默认多维数据集
delete key and let's replace it with a
删除密钥并将其替换为
new object you might remember the hot
新物件你可能还记得火热
key for that is shift a and as I
关键是使用Shift a键并按I键
mentioned before you usually want what
之前提到的你通常想要什么
is underneath mesh cuz these are your
在网格下面 因为这些是你的
Primitives
原语
so we want to start with something that
所以我们想从一些东西开始
most resembles what it is we're building
最像我们正在建造的东西
you if it was a house you might start
如果这是一栋房子 你可能会开始
with a cube if it was a vase you might
如果它是一个花瓶 你可以用一个立方体
start with a cylinder in our case we
在我们的例子中 从一个圆柱体开始
want the donut shaped one although
想要甜甜圈形状的吗？
mathematicians call it a Taurus for some
数学家称它为金牛座
reason so let's add that now if I zoom
原因 所以现在让我们添加如果我放大的话
in by scrolling up we can see we have
通过向上滚动我们可以看到我们有
something resembling a dut looks like a
类似于DUD的东西看起来像一个
pretty weak looking dut you know very
看起来很虚弱 你知道吗？
flimsy looks like the the doughnut
脆弱看起来就像甜甜圈
before it's cooked when they just drop
在它煮熟之前 当它们掉下来的时候
it into the vat and it's just this
放进大桶里 就是这样
little wispy thing um so immediately
小小的小东西 嗯 这么快
after you do some actions in blender you
在搅拌机中执行一些操作后
have options to change it and the
有选项可以更改它 并且
options are hidden down here in the
选项隐藏在下面的
bottom left hand corner you see a little
你可以在左下角看到一点
box and if you click that box you see
框 如果您点击该框 您会看到
options and look we can change the
选项和外观 我们可以更改
dimensions of our Taurus now something
我们金牛座的维度现在有些东西
to note is that these options in blender
需要注意的是 搅拌机中的这些选项
only appear immediately after you have
只有在你有了
done that action if you do another
如果你做另一个动作 你就会做那个动作
action like say deselect your Taurus by
像这样的操作：取消选择你的金牛座
mistake it's gone right because blender
错了 它走对了 因为搅拌机
has assumed you have moved on you've
假设你已经向前看了你已经
accepted the state of your donut and
接受了你甜甜圈的状态
this is the one you want right now if
这是你现在想要的 如果
you haven't done anything drastic or
你没有做过什么过激的事情或
changed this object in some severe way
以某种严重的方式更改了此对象
you can temporarily bring it back by
你可以暂时把它带回来
hitting F9 I never actually remember
按F9键我从来都不记得
that hotkey I just remember that
那个热键我只记得
immediately after I have uh added an
就在我呃添加了一个
object if I want to tweak it now's my
反对 如果我想调整的话现在是我的
chance before I move on to something
在我继续做某事之前的机会
else okay so we could change you know
否则 好的 这样我们就可以改变你知道的
the size of it here we can also change
这里的大小我们也可以改变
the resolution I'll use the term
我将使用这个术语来解决这个问题
resolution Loosely um to uh to make it
决议松散地 嗯 让它
higher or lower Fidelity and a mistake
保真度的高低和一个错误
that a lot of beginners make and I say
这是很多初学者做的 我想说
this because this was the exact mistake
这是因为这正是一个错误
I made way back in 2003 when I started
早在2003年 当我开始
learning blender is they go well I need
学习搅拌机他们进行得很好 我需要
a a realistic looking donut so I guess I
A一个看起来很逼真的甜甜圈 所以我想我
need to go really high resolution I
需要达到非常高的分辨率
remember my first project one of my
还记得我的第一个项目吗
first projects was for a high school
第一个项目是一所高中
film project and I wanted to have a
电影项目和我想要有一个
closeup of a face didn't realize faces
一张脸的特写没有认出脸
were going to be difficult but I went
会很难 但我去了
really high poly and then it was just an
非常高的聚合度 然后它只是一个
absolute nightmare to work with so the
与之合作绝对是噩梦 所以
problem the reason you don't want this
问题是你不想要这个的原因
is that for starters things that are
对于初学者来说 这些都是
high poly are very slow to render and
高多边形渲染速度非常慢 且
they're very hard to work with if you
他们很难合作 如果你
want to tweak the shape of it but also
想要调整它的形状 但也
as you learn and you grow with 3D you'll
随着你的学习和3D的成长 你将会
discover that it is a lot easier to add
发现添加它要容易得多
resolution to something later on but is
以后要解决的问题 但是
very difficult to take it away if you've
很难把它拿走 如果你已经
already built it into it and you don't
我已经把它放进去了 但你没有
need it so long way to say what we
需要这么长的路才能说出我们想说的
actually want is to have as few Poes
实际上想要的是拥有尽可能少的POE
these are called poy uh as you can get
这些被称为POY 呃 正如你能得到的
away with so I'm going to go with 32
所以我要选32个
major and 12 minor and don't worry that
大调和12小调 别担心
it looks all Jagged because we will fix
它看起来完全参差不齐 因为我们会修好的
that in a moment now the major and minor
在这一刻 大调和小调
this is really up to you but I find that
这真的取决于你 但我发现
something that looks uh looks kind of
一些看起来呃看起来有点像
chunky like a fat donut just looks
胖乎乎的甜甜圈 看起来
really delicious so I'm going with
真的很好吃 所以我要和
something
某物
around about this size okay and once I'm
大约这个大小 好的 一旦我
happy with this once I'm ready to click
一旦我准备好点击 我就会很满意
off I click off the options are gone and
关闭我点击关闭选项消失了
this is it this is the donut that I am
就是这个 这就是我的甜甜圈
now working with so how do we make this
现在我们要做的就是让这一切
look higher resolution less Jagged well
看起来分辨率更高 锯齿更少
one way is to use smooth shading so if
一种方法是使用平滑明暗处理 以便在
you rightclick with your object selected
在选定对象的情况下右键单击
go to shade
到阴凉处去
smooth and look at that this is
平滑 看这是
immediately better without getting too
立即好转 但不会变得太好
technical this is kind of a fakery it's
从技术上讲 这是一种伪造的东西
sort of like the Shader is telling the
有点像着色器在告诉
renderer that this is a really high poly
渲染器这是一个非常高的多边形
dense mesh when it really isn't it's
密实的网状结构 但实际上并非如此
just basically kind of like averaging
基本上就像是平均
out uh V uh faces and anyway it's very
嗯 面孔 不管怎么说 它是非常
technical but basically means it's not
技术上 但基本上意味着它不是
going to add anything to your render
要向您的渲染添加任何内容
time but it's going to look smoother and
但它看起来会更流畅
so this is generally what you want for
所以这通常就是你想要的
something that is smooth and and organic
一些光滑的、有机的东西
looking like we want if you were
看起来像我们想要的 如果你是
rendering like architectural or like
渲染方式类似于建筑或类似
hard surfaces like later on we're going
坚硬的表面 就像我们稍后要去的
to put this on a counter then the object
把这个放在柜台上 然后这个物体
would obviously want to be flat but in
显然想要持平 但在
our case we're just going to use shade
在我们的案例中 我们将使用遮阳板
smooth but you might notice that looking
很流畅 但你可能会注意到
at this especially if you go side on
尤其是当你站在一边的时候
that you've got this sort of uh Jagged
你有这种 呃 锯齿状的
shape around here right so the
就在这里的形状 所以
silhouette is really breaking that
剪影真的打破了
illusion that this is a high poly or a
错觉这是一个高度的多边或一个
smooth looking donut but thankfully
甜甜圈看起来很光滑 但谢天谢地
rather than adding all of that complex
而不是添加所有这些复杂的东西
density into the mesh itself and then
将密度添加到网格本身 然后
making it hard to remove later on there
使得以后很难在那里移除它
is another way through modifiers so if
是通过修饰符的另一种方式 因此如果
we go over here to our properties right
我们从这里走到我们的酒店
this very confusing lots of option
这是非常令人困惑的许多选择
looking properties click on the wrench
查看属性 点击扳手
and this is the section called modifiers
这是被称为修饰语的部分
and this is one of those uh object
这是那些呃物体中的一个
dependent uh things so if you've got
依赖于 呃 所以如果你有
your camera selected you won't see it so
你的相机选了 你不会看到的
it's only when you've got actual meshes
只有当你有真正的网格时才会这样
that you might see uh this uh this
你可能会看到这个
modifier here so it's much easier to
这里的修饰语 所以更容易
explain if we just add one so up here
解释一下 如果我们只在上面加一个
add modify and you got a range of
加上MODIFY 就会得到一个范围
options here that can do a whole number
这里的选项可以做一个整数
of things the one that we're looking for
我们正在寻找的东西中
is underneath generate and it is called
在Generate下面 它被称为
subdivision surface and it is a really
细分曲面 它是一个真正的
common modifier that you use all the
您使用的所有
time in fact it's so common it's
事实上 时间是如此普遍 以至于
actually you can just immediately add it
实际上 您可以立即添加它
to any object just by hitting control
任何对象 只需按下Ctrl键
one but don't do that cuz we've already
一次 但不要那么做 因为我们已经
got it so there now some of you might
明白了 所以现在你们中的一些人可能会
have just discovered that your donut has
我刚刚发现你的甜甜圈
disappeared if that is the case you need
如果这就是你需要的话就消失了
to go to edit preferences and then
要转到编辑首选项 然后
underneath viewport where it's got
在它所在的视区下
subdivision at the very bottom disable
禁用最底部的细分
GPU subdivision that will then make the
GPU细分 然后将使
subdivision perform on your CPU instead
改为在CPU上执行细分
instead of your GPU which is maybe
而不是你的GPU 这可能是
nonexistent or not performing whatever
不存在或不执行任何操作
um but disable that and it should appear
嗯 但禁用它 它应该出现
but if it's already working for you
但如果它已经对你起作用了
don't disable it keep it going cuz GPU
不要禁用它 让它继续运行 因为GPU
will be faster so what exactly is this
会更快所以这到底是什么
doing well it's a lot easier to explain
做得很好 解释起来容易多了
if we look at the shade flat mode
如果我们看一下阴影平坦模式
because we're not being uh tricked by
因为我们不会被呃欺骗
the the smooth shading there um if I set
那里的平滑阴影 如果我设置的话
this levels viewport to zero this is our
此级别视口调为零这是我们的
original mesh this is before we add the
原始网格这是在我们添加
subsurface essentially when we increase
本质上是当我们增加的时候
this you can see that it is adding
您可以看到它正在添加
resolution to our mesh and the more I
对我们的网状结构的分辨率越高
increase this viewport levels here uh
在这里增加这个视窗级别呢
the finer and finer that detail becomes
细节就变得越细腻
so to explain it because this is such a
所以要解释一下 因为这是一个
very very common uh modifier it's kind
很常见 很普通的修饰语 很友好
of important to understand how it's
重要的是要了解它是如何
working you can see that uh this is uh
工作你可以看到 呃 这是呃
these squares here these are called
这些正方形在这里被称为
Faces by the way and and for each one of
顺便说一句 每个人的脸和
these faces here as I add a level you
当我为你添加一个关卡时 这里的这些面孔
can see it's becoming four faces right
我可以看到它变成了四张脸 对吧
and then now if I zoomed in on this one
现在如果我放大这张图
one face here if I do another level
如果我做另一个层次 这里的一张脸
that's now become four faces and then if
现在变成了四张脸 然后如果
I zoom in again it's now become four
我再次放大 现在已经是四点了
faces so it's exponentially adding
面孔 所以它是指数相加的
detail and you might also know that it
详细信息 您可能也知道它
is smoothing it out as well like this
就像这样把它弄平了
Jagged Edge that we've got here you can
我们这里有锯齿状的边缘 你可以
see now becomes smoother so to quickly
现在看起来更顺畅了 所以很快
visualize that if I just draw like
想象一下 如果我像这样画
imagine you've got like a 90 Dee uh
想象一下 你有一把90Dee 呃
corner right like this if you add a Subs
如果您添加SuB 右角就像这样
surf modifier what it's going to do is
SURF修改器它要做的是
it's going to add uh a point here right
它会在这里 呃 增加一点
because this is uh the extra detail it's
因为这是 呃 额外的细节
also going to take that point there and
我也会把这一点放在那里
it's going to average it out it's going
它会把它平均出来 它会
to average it out between these points
在这两个点之间求平均值
and it's going to create another one
它将创造出另一个
there and another one there so you go
那里还有另一个 所以你去吧
then from having that really hard corner
然后从那个非常艰难的弯道
there to having something that looks a
拥有一些看起来像是
lot smoother so it's going to take a
顺畅多了 所以要花上一段时间
point and it's also going to uh change
这一点也将呃改变
it to make it look smoother gener
它让它看起来更流畅更普通
speaking so there we go um so now as I
说到这里 嗯 就像我现在一样
increase this you can see it's getting
增加这个 你可以看到它正在变得
uh smoother and smoother now the reason
呃 现在越来越平稳了 原因是
there are two options here you've got
这里有两个选项
levels viewport and levels render so
层级视区和层级渲染方式
reminder this gray area that we operate
提醒这个灰色地带 我们正在运作
in is called our viewport the render is
在中称为我们的视区 渲染为
the pretty version so as an example um
作为一个例子 这个漂亮的版本
you could see if I just turned it off
你可以看到如果我把它关掉
for the viewboard it looks very Jagged
从观景板上看 它看起来很参差不齐
but then for my render if I increase
但是对于我的渲染来说 如果我增加
that to three if I do my render which
如果我做我的渲染 那就是三
you could go up there F uh and render
你可以去那里 呃 然后渲染
image or remember the hotkey F12 you can
图像或记住热键F12您可以
see that that donut is now smooth but I
注意那个甜甜圈现在是光滑的 但我
go back and you can see it's Jagged so
回到过去 你可以看到它是锯齿状的 所以
the viewport you want to generally keep
您通常要保留的视区
it lightweight and then the render time
它轻量级 然后是渲染时间
that's where you want to get uh a really
这就是你想要的 呃 一个真正的
nice looking pretty image so you want to
看起来很漂亮的形象所以你想
often have two different levels um in
通常有两个不同的级别
our case though I don't really think we
我们的案子虽然我不认为我们真的
need to go beyond one even for our final
即使是在我们的决赛中 我们也需要超越一个
pretty image um because this with uh
很漂亮的形象 嗯 因为这和呃
shade smoothing turned on is good enough
打开阴影平滑效果就足够好了
and we're going to be adding more to the
我们将增加更多的
scene later on so we don't want to make
所以我们不想再拍了
it too complex so this is actually
它太复杂了 所以这实际上
pretty good okay so we have a perfect
很好 好的 我们有一个完美的
dut and that's the problem it's too
Dut 这就是问题 它也是
perfect you could spend decades trying
完美的你可以花几十年的时间去尝试
to develop a machine in the real world
在现实世界中开发一台机器
that make it that made a donut this
把甜甜圈做成了这个
perfect and you never would this is so
完美 你永远不会 这是如此的
mathematically precise that the eye will
从数学上讲 眼睛会
always see this as looking fake so
总是认为这看起来很假 所以
that's actually a problem you learn
这实际上是一个你学到的问题
pretty quickly in 3D that things that
在3D中非常快的东西
are too perfect just look fake so you
太完美了 只是看起来很假 所以你
have to spend time making things look
必须花时间让事情看起来像是
misshapen and adding variation there
在那里变形和添加变化
like you see in the real world because
就像你在现实世界中看到的那样 因为
your eye expects to see it so how do we
你的眼睛期待着看到它 那么我们怎么
do that how do we make this doughnut
我们怎么做这个甜甜圈呢？
look a little more lumpy and interesting
看起来更凹凸不平 更有趣
I do that by changing the mesh itself so
我通过改变网格本身来做到这一点
this mode that we are in right now where
我们现在所处的这种模式
we can uh you know click on different
我们可以 你知道 点击不同的
objects is called object mode and I know
对象被称为对象模式 我知道
that because in the top leftand corner
因为在左上角
you can see we are in object mode but if
您可以看到我们处于对象模式 但如果
I click the drop down you can see I get
我点击您可以看到的下拉列表
a number of other options options here
此处有多个其他选项选项
and these options again will change
而这些选项将再次发生变化
depending on the object you've got
取决于您所拥有的对象
selected if I've got a lamp my little
选择如果我有一盏灯我的小
light there selected you can see I've
光在那里选择 你可以看到我已经
only got object mode my camera I've only
只有对象模式我的相机我只有
got object mode but a mesh will give you
获得对象模式 但网格将为您提供
extra options here so let's enter into
这里有额外的选项 让我们进入
edit mode
编辑模式
ooh right now you can see our mesh our
哦 现在你可以看到我们的网状结构
sorry our object has become something
抱歉 我们的物品变成了某种东西
that looks weird it's got a bunch of uh
看起来很奇怪 它有一堆呃
little points on it with lines and very
上面有小点 有线条 很
technical well that's because this is
技术上来说 那是因为这是
actually what the mesh is made up of
实际上 网格是由什么组成的
these little points here which you can
这里的这些小点 你可以
click on just by selecting are called
只需选择Are Call即可点击
your vertices the singular term is
你的顶点单数项是
called vertex I never say that I like to
叫顶点我从来没说过我喜欢
just call all of them vertices
就叫它们所有的顶点吧
regardless of whether it's one or two
不管是一个还是两个
just because you always get some
只是因为你总能得到一些
comments that go um actually it's called
那些评论 呃 实际上它被称为
vertex if it is singular anyway so these
顶点 如果它是单数的 那么这些
are called your vertices and if you have
称为你的顶点 如果你有
two of them joined by a line that is
其中两个由一条线连接 这条线是
called an edge and if you have four of
称为边缘 如果你有四个
them forming uh a face then it's called
他们形成了一张脸 那就叫
a face so with these I can quickly
一张脸 有了这些 我可以很快
change the shape of my object by using
使用更改对象的形状
the same hot Keys as before and if I
和以前一样的快捷键 如果我
want to move this then I would simply
想要移动这个 那么我会简单地
tap G right and you can see it's now
向右点击G 你可以看到它现在
attached to my cursor and then if I want
连接到我的光标上 然后如果我想
to confirm its movement I just do a
为了确认它的运动 我只做了一个
single left click and there it is now if
点击一下鼠标左键 就可以看到
I go back into object
我回到了对象中
mode like that you can see that my mesh
像这样的模式 你可以看到我的网格
has changed okay and by the way the hot
已经变好了 顺便说一句 火辣的
key for jumping in and out of object and
用于跳入和跳出对象的键和
edit mode is Just Tab okay so you can
编辑模式只需按Tab键即可
see it's just toggling between those two
看 它只是在这两者之间来回切换
modes because it's so common that you
模式 因为它是如此普遍 你
want to just quickly change things that
想要快速改变一些事情
it's just uh easily accessible by that
只是 呃 通过那个很容易到达
now this is okay right but you can see
现在这是可以的 但是你可以看到
it's like it's got like some artifacting
它就像是在做一些人造的东西
it's like it's not the greatest lump
好像这不是最棒的肿块
right so how do we make it look a little
好的 那么我们怎么让它看起来有点
more uh natural well I mean you could
更自然的 嗯 我是说你可以
you know you move one drag it out Okay
你知道你走了一步把它拖出来好吗
click and then I move oh the next one
点击 然后我移动 哦 下一个
next to it right I'll move that out and
在它右边 我会把它搬出去 然后
then I'll move this one out a little bit
那我就把这个往外移一点
and then and then I move this one it's
然后 然后我移动这个 它是
like okay well now I've got the thing
就像好的 好的 现在我有了
but it took me like five action
但这花了我五个动作
ridiculous right no one wants to do that
可笑的是 没有人想那样做
no one's got time for that thankfully
谢天谢地 没人有时间这么做
there is a tool in blunder uh just for
在错误中有一个工具 呃 只是为了
this and it's called proportional
这个叫做成比例
editing and you can enable it up there
编辑 您可以在上面启用它
in your toolbar so if you enable that
在您的工具栏中 所以如果启用该选项
now if I hit G and I move it out you
现在 如果我按下G 然后把它移出你
will see I get a little ring around my
我会看到我的周围戴着一枚小戒指
cursor there and that is now changing uh
光标在那里 现在正在改变 嗯
the mesh around it now a lot of people
它周围的网眼现在有很多人
in my previous tutorials were like I
在我之前的教程中我是这样的
don't see what's what's going on you
我看不出你是怎么回事
have to have something selected first
必须先选择一些东西
and then when you hit G you will see uh
然后当你按G键的时候你就会看到
that uh that little circle of influence
那个 呃 那个小圈子的影响力
okay now this circle of influence if I
好的 现在这个影响圈如果我
scroll down sorry if I scroll up you can
向下滚动抱歉 如果我向上滚动 你可以
see it's shrinking its circle of
看 它正在缩小它的圈子
influence and if I scroll down it is
影响 如果我向下滚动它就是
expanding its influence so it's only
扩大它的影响力 所以它只是
going to affect what is in that uh that
会影响到那个呃那个里面有什么
ring there okay if you are on uh yeah if
给那里打电话 如果你在 呃 好的 如果
you don't have a mouse with a scroll
你没有带卷轴的鼠标
wheel you can also change the influence
你还可以改变轮子的影响
by using page up and page down and if
使用PAGE UP和PAGE DOWN 如果
you don't have page up or page down
你没有翻页或翻页
because you're on a Mac keyboard then
因为你用的是Mac键盘
what you would have to do is go to
你要做的就是去
keymap and then change your page up and
快捷键映射 然后更改页面并
page down to something else just so that
翻到其他地方 这样就可以了
you could get around that but guys you
你可以绕过这一点 但伙计们
got to get a mouse get a mouse with a
我要买只老鼠 买只有
scroll wheel I think they're I don't
滚轮 我想他们是我不是
know 50 cents or just in the nearest
知道50美分 还是在最近的
landfill somewhere get a mouse cuz it's
在垃圾填埋场找只老鼠 因为它
going to make uh your life in 3D a lot
会让你的3D生活变得 呃 很多
easier okay so with this I can now uh
更简单 好的 有了这个 我现在可以
make quick work of uh of lumpy shapes
快速处理呃一些笨重的形状
okay so I just drag that out okay I've
好的 我只是把它拖出来 好的 我已经
got a little lumpy shape there maybe I
可能是我的身体有点凹凸不平
go down here and I pull this up just by
走到这里 我把这个拉上来
hitting G moving it up okay so already
敲击G 把它往上移 好的 所以已经
this is looking a little more natural
这看起来更自然了一点
right cuz even if we were making a
对 因为即使我们做了一个
stylized world for a Pixar movie or
皮克斯电影的风格化世界或
something like that you can't have just
像这样的事情 你不能就这样
a a spherical looking donut sorry
一个球形的甜甜圈 对不起
spherical round looking circular
球形圆形看起来像圆形
doughnut cuz it just your eye will see
甜甜圈 因为它只有你的眼睛能看到
it as fake so very quickly I'm able to
它是假的 所以我很快就能
add a little bit of variation to the dut
在DUT中添加一点变化
um just all around it just a little bit
嗯 只是围绕着它 只是一点点
over here and you can see that I am uh
在这里 你可以看到我是呃
just changing my circle of influence
只是在改变我的影响力圈
depending on what size of a a lump I
取决于肿块的大小
want to make so if I just want to make
如果我只是想做的话
like a little bit that sticks out I can
就像一点我能突出的东西
make a small Circle just by scrolling up
只需向上滚动即可形成一个小圆圈
like that um and you just want to do
就像这样 嗯 你只是想做
that until you get something that
直到你得到一些东西
looks a little more natural I might want
我可能想要看起来更自然一点
to make the the inner part as well maybe
也许是为了让内部也变得更好
just drag that in with a smaller
只要把它拖进一个小一点的
Circle and that's pretty good let's just
圆圈 这很好 我们就这样
have a look from the top I might
从上面看一看 我可能会
actually just drag that out make it a
实际上 只是把它拖出来 让它成为
little bit more like
更像是
that but there you go that's pretty good
但这就对了 这很好
for a donut it's still kind of simple
对于一个甜甜圈来说 这仍然是一种简单的
it's not too detailed um but it's got
它不是太详细 但它有
just enough variation in it that uh it's
只是有足够的变化 呃 它是
more interesting to look at oh one more
看起来更有趣哦 再来一次
thing forgot to mention go back into
有件事忘了提回去了
edit mode with tab um Donuts when
使用选项卡UM甜甜圈编辑模式
they're sitting in the uh little vat
他们坐在呃小桶里
thing right uh they're only like half
对的 呃 他们只有一半
submerged then they have to be flipped
浸入水中 然后他们必须被翻转
uh but it means that the bit that's
呃 但这意味着那部分
nearest to the surface is getting less
离地表最近的地方越来越少
heat so essentially what I'm saying is
所以本质上我要说的是
the bit that's around the the dut the
尘土周围的一小块
the circumference of it is usually a
它的周长通常是
little bit flatter so Donuts aren't like
奉承一点 这样甜甜圈就不像
perfectly round all the way around they
它们的周围都是完美的圆形
usually a little bit flatter so what I
通常会有一点奉承 所以我
want to do is I want to select these
我想要做的是我想选择这些
vertices along here and then I want to
顶点沿着这里 然后我想要
shrink them now I could go around one by
缩小它们现在我可以绕着它们走一圈
one like this which is actually what I
像这样的 这实际上就是我
used to do when I was uh learning
我在呃学习的时候经常这样做
blender pre YouTube days and there was
搅拌机在YouTube之前的日子里
uh no tutorials what I would I would do
呃 没有教程 我会怎么做
this if I wanted to select this silly
如果我想选择这个愚蠢的
because there's a a a function a tool
因为有一种功能 一种工具
for that and it is Edge select so if you
对于该选项 请选择边缘 如果您
hold down alt on your keyboard board and
按住键盘上的Alt键并
then do a single left click on not the
然后单击鼠标左键 而不是
points but on the edge right this little
分数 但在边上 就在这个小点上
line here you can see it's selected all
这里的行您可以看到它已全部选中
the way around so it's anything that's
所以它是任何可以
connected along that line is now
沿着这条线连接的是现在
selected so if I want to shrink this
已选中 因此如果我想要缩小此
right what would I do well I mean yeah
好的 我能做好什么 我是说 是的
you could like move it around right we
你可以把它搬来搬去 对不对
want to shrink it we want to change the
想要缩小它我们想要改变
scale of it so we would change we would
它的规模 所以我们会改变我们会
use the hotkey S for scale so s and I'm
用S热键来刻度 所以我和S
going to scale that in and I actually
我要把它放进去 我实际上
don't want proportional editor so I'm
我不想要比例编辑 所以我
going to turn that off and now scale in
我要把它关掉 现在把它放进去
and just make it a little bit flatter
让它变得更平淡一点
and there you go see just feels a little
在那里 你看 只是感觉有点
bit more natural doesn't it looks a
更自然一点 是不是看起来
little bit closer to what a donut looks
更接近甜甜圈的样子
like and by the way don't worry if yours
喜欢 顺便说一句 如果你的
doesn't look exactly like this like your
看起来不完全像你的
lump is a little bit off like some
Lump有点不像
people get a little bit too precious
人们变得有点太珍贵了
with the G I got to match exactly
有了G 我就可以完全匹配了
everything I do like I'm just working on
我所做的每一件事都像是在努力
the fly as well so just make what you
苍蝇也一样 所以你只要做你想做的
think looks good maybe you think this is
觉得看起来不错也许你觉得这是
not misshapen enough and you want to add
还不够畸形 你想要添加
more go for it because it might actually
更多的人去做 因为它可能实际上
turn turn out better than what mine is
结果比我的要好
now before we move to the next part um
现在在我们进入下一部分之前
how to save how to save blender very
如何节省如何非常节省搅拌机
very easy you just go save as and you
非常简单 您只需将其另存为即可
just get one file it's called dot blend
只需获取一个文件 该文件名为点混合
um very literal file extension really
嗯 非常直白的文件扩展名
pushing the limits of what a file
挑战什么文件的极限
extension can be that's almost a word
延伸可以是那几乎是一个词
blender anyway um dot blend and that's
搅拌机不管怎样 嗯 点混合 那是
it and then next time you open it up
然后下一次你打开它
it's exactly like it it's not like
一模一样 不像
zbrush where you got like four or five
ZBrush在那里你得到了四五个
different ways to save a project or an
用不同的方式保存项目或
object or a tool
对象或工具
hate zbrush okay um that's how you save
讨厌ZBrush好吧 嗯 这就是你省下的钱
now also finally I will say uh if you
现在也是最后 我会说 如果你
need help because I know if you if
我需要帮助 因为我知道如果你
you're stuck and then you leave a a
你卡住了 然后你留下了一个a
YouTube comment you might not get a
YouTube上的评论你可能得不到
reply uh if you want immediate help I've
回复 如果你需要立即帮助 我已经
got a Discord so I'll put the link uh
有一个不和谐 所以我会把链接
below so there's like a little channel
下面有一条小小的通道
in there where you can just ask for
在那里你可以只要求
specific uh donut help so if you're
具体的 呃 甜甜圈 所以如果你
having issues uh feel free to jump into
有问题 呃 你可以尽情投入
that and also guys don't beat yourself
还有 男人不会打败你自己
up like 3D is definitely a uh has like a
像3D这样的肯定是一个呃像一个
steepish learning curve so you're in
陡峭的学习曲线 所以你在
that that steep slope right now and it's
现在那个陡峭的斜坡和它
it's really common like a lot of this
这真的很常见 就像很多这样
stuff is very foreign 3D is very unique
东西很异国 3D很独特
it's very different to a lot of 2D tools
它与许多2D工具非常不同
um but don't give up like it's it's
嗯 但不要放弃 就像这是
definitely achievable to learn and
绝对可以学习和实现
self-learn at home you don't have to go
在家里自学--你不必去
to school you don't have to pay for a
去上学你不需要付学费
tutor um it's really easy to uh to get
家教 嗯 真的很容易 呃
help online nowadays so do make use of
现在在线帮助 所以一定要利用
that Discord um post uh comments as well
那个不和嗯也发表了呃评论
in the YouTube comment if you want to um
如果你想 请在YouTube评论中
but I hope hope you stay with it so if
但我希望你能坚持下去 这样如果
you're ready to jump to the next part
您已经准备好跳到下一部分了
after you've saved your blend file go
保存混合文件后 开始
ahead click here and I will see you
前进点击这里我会见到你
there
那里